<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portland Real Estate Journal</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Nick Shivers Team is to be your best resource for Portland Metro &amp; Southwest Washington real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Nick Shivers Team, your professional Portland Metro &amp; Southwest Washington Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="portlandrealestatejournal.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 10:09:13 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 10:09:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trends You Should Expect to See During the 4th Quarter</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9saiZA6OnO0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the fourth quarter, our super-hot seller’s market will transition into more of a neutral market. However, our market is still in great shape overall.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you expect from our Portland Metro/Southwest Washington market during the fourth quarter? &lt;strong&gt;There are several trends you’ll want to watch out for.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the average number of days homes spend on the market will increase. This means if you’re listing your house, you probably won’t be able to sell it as quickly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should also see inventory increase. During October 1 and 2 of this year, there were 169 expired listings (properties that hit the market but didn’t sell) in the Portland Metro area. During the same two-day period in 2017, there were 63 expired listings. And in 2016, there were just 48. Why the increase? People are overpricing their properties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, price appreciation will slow down. However, since real estate is micro-local, certain areas and certain price points will see some nice appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There will be fewer home sales compared to the fourth quarter of 2017.%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/trends-you-should-expect-to-see-during-the-4th-quarter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There will be fewer home sales compared to the fourth quarter of 2017.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also expect the Federal Reserve to raise interest rates. They’re scheduled to meet two more times this year, so you can bet that they’ll raise rates so they can then take them back down and spur growth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, there will be fewer home sales compared to the fourth quarter of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll see our super-hot seller’s market shift into more of a neutral market.&lt;/strong&gt; In some areas, we might even see a buyer’s market emerge. The good news is, our market is still great and our economy is still growing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any other questions about our market or you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 16:21:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/trends-you-should-expect-to-see-during-the-4th-quarter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/trends-you-should-expect-to-see-during-the-4th-quarter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Keys for Buyers to Take Advantage of Our Shifting Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5luRYggYOog?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our Portland market is shifting, so as a buyer, you need great intel and you need to look at all the comparable homes sold yourself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our market is shifting here in Portland, and there are two keys to finding the right home if you’re a buyer.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, when I say a “shifting market,” I mean we’re shifting into a neutral-to-slightly-depreciating market. As we know, real estate is micro-local, and certain areas are still in a strong seller’s market. Overall though, the Portland market is shifting. We’re seeing more price reductions and homes are spending more days on the market. Specifically, we’ve seen a 63% increase in price reductions year over year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that being said, the first key to taking advantage of these conditions is &lt;strong&gt;intel.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to make sure your agent is asking sellers lots of questions. Do they understand that we’re in a shifting market? They should be able to provide data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you’ve had a tough time finding the right house, the fourth quarter will be a great time to get in the game.%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/2-keys-for-buyers-to-take-advantage-of-our-shifting-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you’ve had a tough time finding the right house, the fourth quarter will be a great time to get in the game.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second key is to &lt;strong&gt;look at the comps yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. You can’t look at comparable homes sold back in June or July, because it was a better market then than the one we have now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of great opportunities for buyers out there right now. There’s more inventory available, and sellers are willing to negotiate. Interest rates are also still historically low—people are freaking out because they’re at 5%, but that’s still an incredible rate. &lt;strong&gt;We should see a seasonal shift downward during the fourth quarter, so that’ll be an even greater opportunity for buyers.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve had a tough time finding the right house, the fourth quarter will be a great time to get in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about our market or you’re thinking of selling a home soon, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 14:00:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/2-keys-for-buyers-to-take-advantage-of-our-shifting-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/2-keys-for-buyers-to-take-advantage-of-our-shifting-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Market Is Shifting—What Does That Mean For Sellers?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YxqpXhOMBOU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do sellers need to know in a shifting real estate market? Today I’ll discuss four key points sellers should think about.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What even is a shifting real estate market? It doesn’t mean that the market is going crazy like it did in 2010; it could mean several different things. For this discussion, I’ll be referencing the market specifically in Portland and Southwest Washington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Portland metro, the shifting market means this: &lt;strong&gt;Year over year, there have been 65% more price drops for the period of this last month.&lt;/strong&gt; There are properties that are worth less money now than they were in, say, May. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, in essence, what you should expect to see in a shifting market—&lt;strong&gt;some values dropping down, longer days on market, and more price reductions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even still, our overall market is healthy. Here are some key points for sellers to think about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Active and pending listings are your key.&lt;/strong&gt; When you’re looking for comps, you can’t look at a property that sold in June or July because the fact is that the May market was better than it is now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. There’s always a seasonal downturn in the fourth quarter.&lt;/strong&gt; Values traditionally peak in July, but they peaked a little earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you overprice your home in a shifting market that has either plateaued or is going down, then you could get yourself in trouble and lose value.%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/the-market-is-shiftingwhat-does-that-mean-for-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you overprice your home in a shifting market that has either plateaued or is going down, then you could get yourself in trouble and lose value.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You need to prepare your home for sale before you list it.&lt;/strong&gt;  In early spring, you could just throw your property on the market without much prepping and still get offers on it, but you can’t do that in this market. Competition from other sellers is hitting the market—you need to be sure that when you’re listing your home, it’s ready to go out of the gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. When listing your home, don’t overprice it.&lt;/strong&gt; If you overprice your home in a shifting market that has either plateaued or is going down, then you could get yourself in trouble and lose value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;remember that real estate is micro-local&lt;/strong&gt;: There are some neighborhoods in the Portland area that still don’t have homes on the market. If  we had to make a forecast for the fourth quarter, &lt;strong&gt;I’d say to expect to see this trend continuing, especially with the seasonal downturn.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning on selling your home, be sure to follow these tips. If you have any questions in the meantime, please feel free to reach out to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 12:55:15 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/the-market-is-shiftingwhat-does-that-mean-for-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/the-market-is-shiftingwhat-does-that-mean-for-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Current Market in the Portland Metro and Southwest Washington</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/elYp7-4DNbc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: cemter;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A shift in the wind of the market has happened and today I am going to explain what it means for you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time once again for The Shiver’s Report, where I talk about the real estate market in the Portland Metro and Southwest Washington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is going on? &lt;strong&gt;I believe that there truly has been a shift in the wind.&lt;/strong&gt; In fact, we are going on four and a half months with fewer sales and more inventory. The reality, though, is that this is probably a good thing. This is because, as buyers already know, it has been a tough market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we talk about inventory, days on market, slowdown, and appreciation, the shift isn’t happening—it’s already here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Portland Metro’s first two weeks of August, &lt;strong&gt;sales are down 8.7%.&lt;/strong&gt; This has been the norm for the last three to three and a half months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, for the first time in Southwest Washington, we saw fewer sales than the year before, even though we had seen a massive pickup. This happened because of affordability—we saw rates drop and then pick up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now people think that there will be a big downturn like in 2009 and 2010. However, the difference between now and then is &lt;strong&gt;our current interest rates are between 4.5% and 4.7%&lt;/strong&gt;, whereas before the crash hit, they were at 6.5%. That’s a 2% difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When we talk about inventory, days on market, slowdown, and appreciation, the shift isn't happening—it’s already here%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/the-current-market-in-the-portland-metro-and-southwest-washington.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When we talk about inventory, days on market, slowdown, and appreciation, the shift isn’t happening—it’s already here”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A 2% difference on a $400,000 property is a 20% difference in purchasing power. Even though affordability is starting to go up, home values in our area are higher than ever before and have hit their peak level. This is true as well in over 60% of all markets in the United States. All of this is good for sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers, meanwhile, are starting to get more opportunities and more homes to choose from. You don’t necessarily have to make multiple offers. If you’re looking below the $400,000 range, though, it’s still a super tight market. If you start stepping above that, especially in the luxury level, we have seen days on market and inventory levels go up significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our market or are interested in buying or selling, please feel free to reach out to me. I would love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 18:39:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/the-current-market-in-the-portland-metro-and-southwest-washington.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/the-current-market-in-the-portland-metro-and-southwest-washington.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Will Artificial Intelligence Take Over the Real Estate Industry?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MvVfXJu42vk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I want to talk about using artificial intelligence (AI) to sell your home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have three topics for you today: robots, artificial intelligence (AI), and Zillow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, Zillow stated that they can get you a 15% more accurate home evaluation with AI. Why is that? They use two different things: structured data and unstructured data. Structured data looks at things such as location, square footage, bedrooms, and bathrooms. Unstructured data focuses on things like countertops and amenities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They are trying to figure out how to be more accurate&lt;/strong&gt; so when they look at pictures they can differentiate between slab granite and tile granite. Their AI will pick up the pixels and differentiate between the landscaping, the facades, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally think this is pretty awesome. AI is a great technology and, as an agent, I think that I would use it. I think that our jobs are still safe and that Zillow is not going to ruin that. That is because even with AI, I think that Zillow will always struggle with being as accurate as a real estate agent when it comes to home evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, there is a property at 9636 Knight Street in Portland that was on the market for $325,000. Zillow says it is worth $345,000 but it did not sell. The fact is, it is probably worth $300,000, so they are off about 14%. &lt;strong&gt;Whether it is 14% higher or lower, that is a big percentage difference in this market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a home at 331 SE 7th Way in Camby, meanwhile, that was a Rocket Listing that Zillow says was worth $377,000. We had an offer on the table for that home for $400,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=AI is a great technology and, as an agent, I think that I would use it.%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/will-artificial-intelligence-take-over-the-real-estate-industry.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“AI is a great technology and, as an agent, I think that I would use it.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that? &lt;strong&gt;It is difficult to get AI to understand market demand.&lt;/strong&gt; While it can look at past sales, it cannot know today what the market demand is and it doesn’t know about a home’s specific, detailed location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The property on Knight Street backs up to a freeway with a huge wall, and that’s going to affect its value. AI will never factor that into the details. Having bad neighbors will affect a home’s value as well. Finally, perception will affect the value. What is the overall perception in the real estate market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, while I do think that Zillow using AI is making it easier for consumers to get a good feel for home values, the fact is that if someone takes it as gospel, they are going to lose a lot of money. This is why I think that you need to have a great real estate professional who knows the market to help you make one of the biggest purchases of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any additional questions or are interested in buying or selling, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to helping you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 10:28:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/will-artificial-intelligence-take-over-the-real-estate-industry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/will-artificial-intelligence-take-over-the-real-estate-industry.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Buyers and Sellers Should Expect From Our SW Washington Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WL8OQNPeP60?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s been going on in our Southwest Washington market lately? Today let’s review how the past few months have fared.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How has our Southwest Washington market fared so far this year? Let’s take a look at the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April, closed sales rose 11%  in Portland and 12% in Southwest Washington as a whole. And in May, Portland saw an 8% drop in closed sales and Southwest Washington overall saw a dip of 7%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about June? Well, much like we saw last month, &lt;strong&gt;June has seen closed sales drop 9% in Portland and 3% across Southwest Washington in general.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do these figures tell us about our market? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One major thing we can take away from these trends is that there’s a sense of apathy among buyers in our market lately. First-time buyers are struggling to secure a home, as listings in lower price points often see six or more offers. Even so, buyer traffic hasn’t been as hot as it should be at this time of year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I am very optimistic that all of the factors we’ve discussed today will ultimately result in a stable summer market.%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/what-buyers-and-sellers-should-expect-from-our-sw-washington-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I am very optimistic that all of the factors we’ve discussed today will ultimately result in a stable summer market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;my hope for the months to come is that we start seeing more listings come onto our market.&lt;/strong&gt; And with the Fed having just raised interest rates, it’s likely that market activity will begin to pick up. Economic growth is strong and unemployment is low, so I am very optimistic that all of the factors we’ve discussed today will ultimately result in a stable summer market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 10:09:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/what-buyers-and-sellers-should-expect-from-our-sw-washington-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/what-buyers-and-sellers-should-expect-from-our-sw-washington-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Take Control of Your Selling Experience With My Rocket Listing</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/II7UOEb87BQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you heard of My Rocket Listing? Today I’d like to explain this great program my team offers and what it can do for you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team and I have sold thousands of homes, and we realize that even in a hot real estate market, some people out there still have the desire to sell without all the hassle of a traditional listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showings, repairs, negotiations, and uncertainty about closing are all aspects of the selling process some would simply rather not deal with. &lt;strong&gt;This is why my team created My Rocket Listing—a program that’s as easy as “three, two, one, sold.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain how this countdown to success looks like for sellers who use this program. Here are each of the steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Contact us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. We’ll run our algorithm and have an on-site evaluation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Within 24 hours, we’ll get an offer for your home and give you a comparative market analysis showing what you could earn in a traditional market setting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The My Rocket Listing program is as easy as three, two, one, sold.%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/take-control-of-your-selling-experience-with-my-rocket-listing.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The My Rocket Listing program is as easy as three, two, one, sold.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With My Rocket Listing, you pick the closing and control the process. About 70% of consumers want a maximum-price offer for their home. But the remaining 30% are more interested in receiving a fair offer with maximum convenience, which is exactly what our program provides. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take one of our past clients, Larry, for example. Larry was moving to Florida and came to us to pursue our My Rocket Listing program. He told me that he just wanted to get the selling process over and done with so he could move on to his next home. The My Rocket Listing offer was perfect for Larry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So whether you’re interested in the My Rocket Listing program or would rather have a traditional listing experience, &lt;strong&gt;my team and I can guarantee transparency and great results when you work with us.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 10:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/take-control-of-your-selling-experience-with-my-rocket-listing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/take-control-of-your-selling-experience-with-my-rocket-listing.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Reasons to Consider a Local Lender</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dKn92zAagFQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you searching for the right lending professional to help you secure a home loan? Consider a local lender.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in a hot seller’s season right now, which means competition among buyers is strong. This leaves many buyers wondering how they can set themselves, and their offer, apart.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Today we are going to talk about why a local lender helps you stand out in a competitive, multiple offer situation.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Our team helps sellers all the time. When we list a property, we look for buyers with more than just a pre-approval letter to reinforce their offer. Our team seeks out buyers who are working with a lender who can back them up, and who would be willing to reach out to us directly. I want a lender to be able to tell my team exactly why it is they believe a buyer is qualified.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;I want this for two reasons:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. If they close deals, I might know them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. I’m talking to them.&lt;/strong&gt; Even in a text and email world, you want to be able to have at least a conversation. If you can’t have a conversation, make sure that lender is sending out a video text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I guarantee any top listing agent is going to look at  Quicken Loans a little bit differently than someone that we know gets deals done.%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/2-reasons-to-consider-a-local-lender.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I guarantee any top listing agent is going to look at  Quicken Loans a little bit differently than someone that we know gets deals done.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, as the consumer, may be thinking you are going to go to Quicken Loans and save a quarter of a percent. Well, the fact is that after everything is done, it’s about the same. Also, I guarantee any top listing agent is going to look at Quicken Loans a little bit differently than someone who we know gets deals done.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;In this market, if you want to win in a multiple offer situation, &lt;strong&gt;you need a lender that is proactive in the market,&lt;/strong&gt; well-known, and willing to reach out on your behalf.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;If you have any further questions about why you should consider a local lender when purchasing your new home, please don’t hesitate to ask. I look forward to speaking with you soon&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 11:31:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/2-reasons-to-consider-a-local-lender.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/2-reasons-to-consider-a-local-lender.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Sell a Home, Save a Child Helps Children in Need Around the Globe</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VCnqrroTNkU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;With our program Sell a Home, Save a Child, we donate a share of our real estate commissions to a program for children in need.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you a quick story about an experience that changed my life forever—for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 10 years ago, I was volunteering at a landfill in Managua, Venezuela to help the people who lived and worked there under destitute conditions. Some of these people were children. My own kids were young at the time, and I saw some things at that landfill that inspired me to help the kids who lived there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got involved with an organization called Forward Edge International, but I realized there was something more I could do. I believe everyone wants to make a difference, but sometimes you just don’t know how. That’s when my good friend Eric Hatch and I started Sell a Home, Save a Child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Sell a Home, Save a Child? It’s a movement. More specifically, it’s a collaboration of agents, title companies, mortgage representatives, builders, transaction coordinators, and other professionals in the real estate industry all around the country who want to make a difference in kids’ lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Want to join the Sell a Home, Save a Child movement?%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/how-sell-a-home-save-a-child-helps-children-in-need-around-the-globe.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Want to join the Sell a Home, Save a Child movement?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For every home sold through this program, we donate 10% of our commission to Forward Edge International&lt;/strong&gt; to help transform the lives of children in Cuba, Haiti, Nicaragua, Kenya, Mexico, and the US. Our goal last year was to raise $1 million. We fell just short of that mark, but we still raised $900,000. That sum can make a big difference in a lot of kids’ lives around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you partner up with Sell a Home, Save a Child? &lt;strong&gt;If you have a home you need to sell or you know someone who does, give us a call.&lt;/strong&gt; For the first home we sell each month, we donate 100% of our commission to Forward Edge International instead of just 10%. Some lucky seller out there will not only get top dollar for their home, but they’ll donate to a good cause at no cost to them whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about Sell a Home, Save a Child or you have any other real estate needs I can assist you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 14:15:23 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/how-sell-a-home-save-a-child-helps-children-in-need-around-the-globe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/how-sell-a-home-save-a-child-helps-children-in-need-around-the-globe.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zillow and Wall Street Are Teaming Up</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rzGwJQIKmUQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zillow has officially entered the home buying and flipping industry. Here&amp;rsquo;s what to expect.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zillow is now buying and flipping homes. This is very interesting because it confirms that Wall Street is now dipping their hand into the real estate cookie jar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we all know that Wall Street isn’t known for being transparent. &lt;strong&gt;That’s what makes the difference between Zillow’s instant offer and our program, “My Rocket Listing,” so stark.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After selling thousands of homes, I’ve realized that there are still people that don’t want to go through the hassle and stress of buying or selling a home. They value convenience over the top list price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People want a guarantee and they want convenience.%20portlandrealestatejournal.com/zillow-and-wall-street-are-teaming-up.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People want a guarantee and they want convenience.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Zillow comes out and gives you an offer on your home, but they are off by an average of 7%, that’s $28,000 on a $400,000 house. With our My Rocket Listing program, we will not only give you an offer, but we will also give you a suggested list price. Even in a hot market like the one we have in Portland, people want a guarantee and convenience. I believe it’s the most transparent way to sell your home. &lt;strong&gt;On average, about two out of 10 people chose the My Rocket Listing program, while the other eight will want us to sell the home traditionally for maximum value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about this topic or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 16:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>portlandrealestatejournal.com/zillow-and-wall-street-are-teaming-up.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">portlandrealestatejournal.com/zillow-and-wall-street-are-teaming-up.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
